<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A declaration of the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament for the protecting of all those that obey the orders and commands of Parliament also declaring all those to be enemies to the Commonwealth and disturbers of the peace of the Kingdom, who either seize, apprehend or detain in prison, or send out their warrants for the apprehending, or otherwise molesting any person or persons for obeying the ordinance and commands of the Parliament, or for refusing to obey the Commission of Array.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B21945</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">10268531</idno>
  <idno type="VID">204623</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240951488</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E1421</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">10268531</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B21945)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 204623)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1382:18)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A declaration of the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament for the protecting of all those that obey the orders and commands of Parliament also declaring all those to be enemies to the Commonwealth and disturbers of the peace of the Kingdom, who either seize, apprehend or detain in prison, or send out their warrants for the apprehending, or otherwise molesting any person or persons for obeying the ordinance and commands of the Parliament, or for refusing to obey the Commission of Array.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>7 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Luke Norton and John Field for E. Husband and J. Franck,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1642.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"September 8. 1642. Ordered by the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament, that this declaration be forthwith printed and published.  H. Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1642-1649.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:204623:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:204623:1"/>
            <p> A DECLARATION OF THE Lords and Commons Assembled in PARLIAMENT, For the Protecting of all those that obey the Orders and Commands of Parliament.</p>
            <p>ALSO, Declaring all those to be Enemies to the Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth, and Disturbers of the peace of the Kingdom, who either seize, apprehend or detain in prison, or send out their Warrants for the apprehending, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise molesting any person or persons for obey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Ordinance and Commands of the Parliament, or for the refusing to obey the Commission of Array.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <opener>
                           <dateline>
                              <date>
                                 <hi>September</hi> 8. 1642.</date>
                           </dateline>
                        </opener>
                        <p>ORdered by the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament, That this Declaration be forthwith printed and published.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>H. Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed by LUKE NORTON and JOHN FIELD, for <hi>E. Husband</hi> and <hi>J. Franck,</hi> and are to be sold at their shops in the Middle-Temple, and next door to the Kings-head in Fleetstreet. <hi>September</hi> 9. 1642.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:204623:2"/>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="declaration">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:204623:2"/>
            <head>A DECLARATION Of the LORDS AND COMMONS IN PARLIAMENT.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas information hath been given, that divers Persons well affected to the peace and safety of the King and Kingdom, have been seised, apprehended and imprison<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ed, and divers worthy Ministers
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:204623:3"/> attached and bound over to the next Assises to be holden at Chester, for yeelding obedience to the Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance and command of Parliament, and for refusing to obey the Illegall commands of the Commissioners of Array; The Lords and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons do therefore hereby declare all those to be Enemies to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monwealth, and disturbers of the peace of the Kingdom, who seize, apprehend, or detain in prison, or send out their Warrants for the ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehending, or otherwise molesting any person or persons for obeying the Ordinances and commands of the Parliament, or for refusing to obey the Commission of Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ray.</p>
            <p>And do require and command all
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:204623:3"/> Lord Lieutenants, Deputy Lieu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenants, Justices of peace, Sheriffs, Majors, Constables, and all other His Majesties Officers and loving Subjects, That they do not onely forbear to execute any Warrants sent out by the Commissioners of Array, for the apprehending or binding over to the Assizes, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwise molesting any of His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties good Subjects, for not yeeld<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing obedience to the Illegall War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants and commands of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners of Array, but that they also assist, to the protection and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of all those who are in danger to be apprehended, oppressed or molested by the violence and ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rannie of the Commissioners of Array:</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:204623:4"/>
            <p> Whereof they require the Justices of Assize of the County Palatine of <hi>Chester,</hi> and the Keeper of the castle of <hi>Chester,</hi> and of other prisons in the said County, and all other His Majesties Officers and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects whom it may concern, to take especiall notice, that so those that are already imprisoned, or bound over by the Commissioners of Array in that County, may be discharged, and no further prosecuted and mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lested by any usurped Power and Authority against the Laws of this Land.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="license">
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:204623:4"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>September 8. 1642.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>Ordered by the Lords and Commons in Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, That this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration bee forthwith Printed and Published.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>H: Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>